Guide to the Jane L. Berdes Papers, 1525-1993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Printed Material Series
  - Libretto Subseries (Box 41)
    - The Opera Libretto Library (Box 41)
    - Antonio Vivaldi (A Guide to Research) (Box 41)
    - Veneziano Europeo (Box 41)
    - Credo (Box 41)
    - Deus tuorum militum (Box 41)
    - Magnificat (Box 41)
    - Laudate pueri Dominum (Box 41)
    - Dixit (Box 41)
    - Magnificat (Box 41)
    - Gloria (Box 41)
    - Vivaldi (Box 41)
    - Oratorio (Box 41)
    - Ariadne on Naxos (Box 41)
    - Joseph and his Brethren (Box 41)
    - Agrippina (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous Vivaldi scores (Box 41)
- Oversize Material
  - Research Notes and Materials Series
    THE NUMBERS IN PARENTHESES FOLLOWING FOLDER TITLES REFER TO FOLDER NUMBERS WRITTEN ON THE FOLDERS IN THE NON-OVERSIZE BOXES FROM WHICH THESE MATERIALS WERE PULLED.
    - Repertoire: (Oversize-box 43)
      - Oratorio/Mendicanti (Oversize-box 43)
      - Incurabile/Oratorio (Oversize-box 43)
      - Sacred Vocal Works, alpha by composer G-F (Oversize-box 43)
    - Archive and Library Holdings (Oversize-box 43)
    - Institution:
      - Derelitti (Oversize-box 43)
      - Pietá; (2) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Mendicanti (3) (Oversize-box 43)
    - Ospedali Grandi:
      - General history in 9 stages (Oversize-box 43)
      - Documents (4) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Documents (8) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Documents (12) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Documents (14) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Documents (15) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Secondary sources (15) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Contemporary commentary (2) (Oversize-box 43)
      - Model for other institutions (2) (Oversize-box 43)
    - Iconography (1) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Iconography (5) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Venice (3) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Venice (7) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Venice (9) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Women musicians in Venice: Chapter III (2) (Oversize-box 44)
    - Raw materials:
      - Repertoire (Oversize-box 44)
      - figlie di Coro (2) (Oversize-box 44)
      - Fact sheet (Oversize-box 44)
      - Musical chronology (Oversize-box 44)
      - Liturgical, state calendars (Oversize-box 45)
      - Maestri and composers (Oversize-box 45)
      - Patrons and benefactors (Oversize-box 45)
      - Government, aristocracy structure (Oversize-box 45)
      - Iconography and instruments (Oversize-box 45)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS): Documents:
      - Volume I (2) (Oversize-box 45)
      - Volume II (2) (Oversize-box 45)
      - Volume III (1) (Oversize-box 45)
      - Volume II (1) (Oversize-box 45)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS) (3) (Oversize-box 45)
    - Women in music (10) (Oversize-box 45)
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS): Rondo (Oversize-box 45)
  - MUSIC SERIES
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS): (Oversize-box 46)
      - Six trios/London, Welcher 1771 Gb Lbm g. 471 (Oversize-box 46)
      - Trio in Bb Major (Modena) 7, marked 24 (Oversize-box 46)
      - String Quartets/Print (London: William Napier, 1733) Gb-Cu MR 320.a.75401 (Oversize-box 46)
      - Violin Sonata in A Major (Oversize-box 46)
      - Duets (Oversize-box 46)
      - Trois Concerts Opus 2/Print (Amsterdam: Hummel, 1772) E-Mn M709-716/9 (Oversize-box 46)
      - 6 Concertos in 9 Parts/Print (London: Napier, 1773)US WC M1012.S62.Op.3 (Oversize-box 46)
  - Research Notes and Materials Series
    - Maddalena Lombardini-Sirmen (MLS):
      - A Concerto/Print (London: Napier, 1772) US-WC M1012.S.62.Op3 (Oversize-box 46)
      - Violin Concerto No. 1 in Bb MSS I - Vnm Cod lt. IV. 1524 (11472) (Oversize-box 46)
      - Concerto (Oversize-box 46)
      - Berdes, editor (Oversize-box 47)
      - Violin Concerto/Berdes, editor (3) (Oversize-box 47)
    - Galuppi (1) (Oversize-box 47)
    - Lodovico Sirmen (LS):
      - Sei Duetti/Print (Venice: Zatta and figlie, c. 1789) (Oversize-box 47)
      - Sei Trii Op.1 (Oversize-box 47)
    - Pampani (Oversize-box 47)
    - Porpora (Oversize-box 48)
    - Miscellaneous (Oversize-box 48)
    - Miscellaneous (2) (Oversize-box 48)
  - MISCELLANEOUS SERIES
    - Music history (1) (Oversize-box 48)